David Sutton

UX Research and Experience Design DavidSutton585@gmail.com 585.298.0769

PROFILE

My passion is working hands-on with businesses to facilitate innovation with a user-centered approach to development. My expertise ranges from User Experience Research and Design to Accessibility and Software Development.

I am founder and director of Upstate UX, a large User Experience Network in Upstate New York, and Crashtest, an RIT institution based on instilling the knowledge and values of iterative, user-first validation and development.

I have designed, validated and executed well-received projects for Xerox, PepsiCo, Apple and Verizon. Accustomed to working in competitive, fast-paced environments with shifting priorities.

Technical Proficiencies

UI/UX PRODUCT DESIGN

- Adobe Creative Suite (Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, Fireworks)
- Sketch App, Framer, Balsamiq,
- Figma, inVision, Axure, Origami, Principal, Adobe XD

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

- HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery,
- Wordpress, PHP, Apache, Jekyll, Hugo, Python, C++, Java, C#

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

B2B SOLUTIONS DESIGN SPECIALIST - 2010-PRESENT

VERIZON AND OTHER LOCAL SMB ORGS

- Uncover business challenges to find and validate innovation opportunities.
- Creating/maintaining web apps and connected hardware for SMB clientele.

CONSULTANT IN UX AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT - 2013-2017

XEROX - UI/UX INTERACTION DESIGN - 2015-2017

UI/UX Design specialist at Xerox in Webster, NY in the Experience Design Group.

- Coordinate across departments and disciplines to shape the user experience DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT across product's web and mobile interfaces and as onboard touchscreen UI.
- Lead in many processes such as design walkthroughs, user feedback sessions and formal usability testing to validate solutions with stakeholders.
- Translate strategy, business requirements and usability best practices into best-in-class digital experiences while ensuring legal and HIPAA compliance.
- Responsible for functional documentation of many products/features including style guides, UX standards.

APPLE - UI/UX DEVELOPER- 2013-2014

UI/UX consultant at Apple Inc. in Cupertino, California.

- Lead design and development of several new products, with a focus on rapid prototyping and web applications development.
- Conducting interviews, contextual inquiry research, in-person and remote usability testing, competitive analysis, to discover innovation opportunities.

EDUCATION

ROCHESTER INSTITUTE OF **TECHNOLOGY**

Concentrations in UX Design and Web Design & Development

CERTIFICATIONS & ASSOCIATIONS

IDEO'S "HUMAN-CENTERED DESIGN" CERTIFICATION

Implementing the core concepts of human-centered design to effect social change.

LUMA INSTITUTE'S "INNOVATION THROUGH USER-CENTERED DESIGN"

Leading a Culture of Innovation, Brainstorming and Product Testing, Prototyping, Ethnographic Research.

UPSTATE UX

Founded UpstateUX for designers, developers, and students to learn, teach & collaborate in Rochester.

• Workshops, conferences, networking events, Q & A discussions, professional development training and general community outreach.

TEACHING INTERACTION **Schools:**

- Rochester Institute Of Technology
- Monroe Community College
- Baltimore School for the Arts

Authored and instructed courses:

- Interaction & UI/UX Design
- Computer Programming (HTML/ CSS, Advanced Java)
- Front-end Web Development
- Facilitated and instructed the IDEO Design Certification Program for over 100 students and professionals.
- Founded & directed the nationally recognized organization "Crashtest", facilitating iterative UX processes.